hello my name is green and welcome back
to a very very weird start to a
hermitcraft episode i'm here in mumbo's
base as you can see behind me and we're
trying to get these villagers to breed
and give us some more farmers basically
for my potato i need some farmers but
for some reason
these guys just
they like they love each other but
they're just not giving us the the
villages that we need it's it's a bit
weird mumbo's scratching his head i mean
i came in and i was like i know what the
problem is so i put down some candles
trying to you know
and you gave them carrots like if a
romantic dinner doesn't solve this
problem i don't know what does and yeah
so now we're just scratching our heads
trying to get this to work i don't know
but we really need these guys to start
working because mumbo's done the whole
system look how complicated this thing
looks
but just no luck at the moment i'm never
using villagers again
no i've got to admit
i don't really know what to do
fortunately iskall has sent over
some
thanks for the help i really didn't i
really didn't do anything useful so what
isgal's done is he sent over some
farmers for me and he's placed them here
just so that my giant rail track
actually gets used so i need to somehow
get these guys onto this track
and i've actually set it all up i've
done some crazy redstone which is
really not like me
i did i did have a little bit of help
yes but i put it all together myself it
took me two hours for this little potato
i'm gonna show you so the idea is they
come all the way down in here all along
this railway and they get thrown
straight into here and if you look
inside the potato
i've actually got a bunch of redstone
look at that so i have created a system
based on the very limited redstone that
i know to create a potato farm basically
i've got i've even added an on and off
switch down the bottom here so
this is how you turn it on and off this
just travels all the way up through the
base and it activates a flippy flippy
tippy flippy flippy flop on every single
level
as you can see right there and that
pushes the observer out because of the
lag we don't we want to reduce lag so
basically if i want to turn this off to
help out the server it will turn off all
of these clocks but what makes this
particular farm a little bit different
from the others is how it transports the
items through so the farmer does his
business and the way it works is they
basically try and farm here but they
can't so they end up throwing these
through well that's not a good sign is
it what have i done wrong here
ah
there's no there's no hopper in here
i've just put i've just put a minecart
down by itself oh no well you kind of
got an idea of how it works so basically
the farmer throws it through
and the items go they pop through a
dispenser like that and you can hear it
it makes its way all the way down
through the potato i'm just breaking
everything so hopefully it all ends up
down here uh
or nearly all down here
the only problem is that sometimes it's
not particularly accurate when it
dispenses it so as you can see there's
some potatoes there
but in theory the villagers should just
pick them up and keep throwing them so
the farmer
so the farmer does his business he's got
all of his potatoes and he tries to farm
here but then he throws them through and
then they get dispensed
all the way down the system till the end
and any of them that don't actually make
it in i think or i hope that the
villager will then pick them up
and keep throwing them in so that's the
theory and now it's time to see if this
will actually work uh i just i just
asked how do i get this villager into
this minecart and the answer is i don't
know and neither does mumbo oh
no
oh well that was a really good test
actually i'm not boating them over i
have to i've committed to this roller
coaster now it's going to happen okay if
i destroy the boat oh i punched him
come on now all i've got to do is get
him in this minecart somehow
i think he's trying to get to mumbo's
village
no no no no
what is he doing
he's in he's in oh that's so much more
effort than it needs to be oh my
goodness okay now in theory all we've
got to do is power this
and he should end up
all the way
in the potato
goodbye
let's follow him because there's
undoubtedly something is going to go
wrong there always is
up he goes we're going to have to name i
was thinking i actually really want to
name these guys really something silly
like i think this guy is going to be
galrog destroyer of worlds
[Laughter]
this is brilliant keep going gal rog
this is also the first time that i've
ever done anything like this with farms
with villagers like i've never worked
with any of this stuff before it's a
really big deal for me and down he goes
this should work without any problems
now because all he's got to do
straight up
yes
villager delivered and that's the top
layer so let's leave him in there for
the time being because i have a feeling
he's just gonna run straight out of here
i think he's already started farming
i've just now got to get rid of this
minecart absolutely
brilliant it really it didn't take long
he's well off
this potato farm is going to be
phenomenal it might not be very
productive but
it's probably going to produce more
potatoes than i will ever need i can't
believe it this is the first time that
anything like this has gone my way last
episode was a really bad time in fact it
was so bad that i've started a new
business venture i talked about it at
the end of last episode before we go and
get the other guy look at this so this
was my like prototype system over here
to see how this would work but since we
don't need this anymore since i'm pretty
sure it all works
i can show you all how poor i am for a
start i have
one diamond left now i plan to change
that with a live stream which may or may
not have already happened hello from the
past everybody so i'm down to my last
diamond because i've invested everything
and i mean everything in this last
venture so i have created my very first
did you die box and this is what you get
you get some armor
uh with varying different enchantments
you get an elytra with mending and
unbreaking you get a trident which is a
really cool thing basically this is like
what i would want if i died you get a
silky shovel a mr axe a diamond sword a
fast pick and a silk pick and it's got
everything you want efficiency 5 all of
them have efficiency 5 and it's a really
really good box to have now that took
a huge amount of my resources to get
so they will be sold for a huge amount
of diamonds because they simply take so
long to make i'm halfway through making
my next one and i started thinking like
oh i could call them something a bit
better so this is the the second did you
die box i've pretty much got everything
i've got um knock knock it's fire cause
this one has knockback and dig yourself
out of shame and don't worry accidents
happen so i think i'm gonna do i'm gonna
make lots of really randomly named tools
but the thing that i need lots of is
elytra so
that's what i'm going to get later on
but you can see that i've got you know
i've got all my tridents i've started um
getting all these books look at all
these books i've got anvils galore
and yeah just seriously i've spent every
diamond that i've got on all of this
stuff and it's not even that's not even
half of it
i've invested everything in this
business venture because i imagine that
at some point people will want it and
hey to me
having one of these boxes is way more
valuable than stacks of diamonds anyway
because this is what i would spend my
diamonds on in an emergency so overall i
think this is a really good business
plan it's just
extraordinarily expensive to make and
it's taken me a day and i've only made
one and a half
so
yeah it's it's really not good anyway
let's go and get this second villager
shall we
there we go and
he's off
apparently iskall has just turned up and
they've they've finally decided that
they're having babies now
well my work here is done what the heck
so iskall turns up and suddenly it
starts working well that's weird anyway
let's go and see if we can find um what
should we call this guy korgoth
weld eater
that's your name
corgoth world eater
what the heck
he's doing some tokyo drift right now
he's not even on the track
he really is a mystical villager i
really hope he doesn't go flying off i
haven't got time to mess about
oh he's on
oh thank goodness and is he in we have
delivered another villager
where did you come from
seriously
i think we should make this more
official if you ask me so let's pop
inside here with uh who are you you're
going to be gareth destroyer of worlds
well
i should have really put destroyer of
potatoes don't you think
yes
yes i do
[Laughter]
and that means that you are balrok
world eater
yes
very well
i shall i shall eat the world
i should have put potato eater
done i've only got two of the villagers
in here i don't actually know if this is
you know sending the potatoes all the
way through i really hope that it is
let's actually go and see the real test
is to see if they're down here if
they're not they're getting stuck yeah
they're getting stuck somewhere
i'm not surprised you know when i said
that this was going well it's not
something is clogging the system where
uh where are these potatoes ending up i
had to get iskal to come and find out
what was wrong and it was the stupidest
thing it's just something that i didn't
know that i had to do so not really
something i did wrong i just didn't know
about it basically this block here
i had the hopper minecart underneath it
you actually need to push the dirt block
inside of it so basically there's it's
one in two in there so yeah it now works
he's being a bit lazy now gareth
destroyer of worlds why aren't you
destroying these potatoes well they are
now done i am just waiting for mumbo's
breeder which is now working by the way
to start producing some farmers so we
can send over the last two for my potato
and you'll also notice that i've added
in this giant line of dirt now it's
going to be messy for a little while but
i am actually going to start working on
the train station something that i've
been threatening to do for about 10
episodes now we're actually gonna start
it the first thing that i really want to
do is to make sure that i place it
almost exactly in between our bases so
the center of my base is actually off to
the side a little bit there so the
center will come all the way down there
and then the center of mumbo's runs all
the way down there so i'm thinking if i
find the exact center uh this way across
here and then i have the center of my
base hit the left hand side and the
center of numbers hit the right hand
side it should really tie our bases
together in this zigzag pattern that
mimics exactly what we've got here
so i'm really hoping that this will come
together but it's going to be a lot of
tedious counting to make sure that that
is in the right place
but i want to go and see how mumbo's
villagers are coming along because i
really really just want to get these
farmers in the tube
he's
i think he's no he's not afk
he hasn't seen
oh my goodness
hold on i've got i've got a prank
since wally doesn't know
since he hasn't got a clue
quickly
sub to green
i'm gonna give him a taste of his own
medicine
[Laughter]
he hasn't he hasn't even noticed me can
i get away with another can i get away
with another i don't think so i think
he's gonna come back up
uh no yeah i'm bailing i'm bailing but
i'm gonna try and i'm gonna get this
right when he starts
when he starts coming up the ladder i'm
gonna bail i can't be caught with this
i'm gonna have to skidaddle around
i've renamed his items
he's coming up he's coming up i need to
time this perfectly
and if i don't take damage i won't make
any noise
oh my goodness i've done it
i renamed his items right under his nose
let's get out of here
quickly
and now i can pretend like i've just
come in
he's just noticed
[Laughter]
i thought that i was going to be able to
do that while he was afk
but i managed to do it right under his
nose
uh-oh oh he sees me
maybe not
he just flew straight over me
the only thing is i don't really know
what we're gonna do with this island
because i have a feeling that the train
station once i've worked it out is going
to end up somewhere around here i'm not
entirely sure but i just i have a
feeling so i think we might want to get
rid of it just to make the whole place
look
like cleaner i think i know who poultry
man is i found i found him i've never
seen this
what the heck did he climb on the
chicken or did they spawn because that
is
really weird i'm gonna leave you to do
do your thing poultry man
i did lose count though back to counting
one two
what the heck
he's just gone
that is really
weird and just like that poultry man
vanished okay so in theory this line
here is the center but just because it's
the mathematical center doesn't mean
that it actually looks right to the eye
and that's kind of important when you're
building in minecraft guys because
as you can see actually that does look
alright but sometimes the mathematical
center see look that looks way closer to
my base than mumbos it looks longer and
it's probably because of this island but
we might need to just shift it over
depending on how it actually looks i
also have a feeling that the architects
are going to be like
30 work and 90
constantly messing with each other i
wonder i reckon that he's going to
rename some of my tools if he gets the
opportunity it's going to be a lot of
fun actually we're going to be working
on a project with three people
potentially if this gal actually decides
to join that's something that i actually
need to sort out fairly shortly is the
letter to iskal inviting him to
architects but assuming that he joins
we're putting three of the most
trolly people together that are gonna
constantly mess with each other i'm
gonna be surprised if we get any work
done at all but anyway minor mumbo's
bases absolutely they look so cool and i
think with this in the middle with uh
like a track or a walkway from one to
the other it will properly connect this
up for the first time and i'm actually
going to put like a giant a on this uh
platform
and it should look like the architect
headquarters
and yeah i'm really excited for this so
let's actually get started shall we
so i'm going to start by making two
pillars one at either end and then from
there we will make the platform that
brings me back to the first episode rock
out rock out we are the drowned
since losing my
if you remember that please let me know
in the comments
been such a long time speaking of which
this is my 51st episode meaning this has
just caught up with my longest running
series on the channel which used to be
evo so the next episode of hermitcraft
will officially be my will make this
series officially my longest running
ever
and that's a really big thing since i've
been doing youtube for such a long time
now so if you've been with me for this
whole journey thank you so much i've
really really enjoyed it so far and i
hope that we can get to at least episode
100 before the season ends but that
depends on when that is i've got no
plans to stop just yet
all right so i've got two pillars and
they're going to be relatively thin i
think i could thicken these up later
that would be really easy so we'll just
start with this for now and see how it
goes so i'm gonna bring it up fairly
high
and then these are gonna
sort of arch out and hold up what i'm
going to be building i can't believe i'm
actually finally making this thing and
that's not even the last thing i have to
make so the plan is that i'll do this
and mumbo will do the redstone for it
that's the that's the plan at the moment
i mean he's probably got an easier job
than me
but i think this won't take too long i'm
not going to make like the most
spectacular train station in the world
it's literally because our our station
the one here it's not a main station
this isn't a district station at all the
district station is going to be over
there where all of the other futuristic
district is but no one actually built
there so maybe this is actually in
reality this is the main one but either
way it's not supposed to be like the
main station although i think i'm just
going to keep it simple because i don't
want to detract from our bases i know
that they're quite big and they kind of
remind me of the two characters from
portal
but i think that this just as a platform
with an a on it should work out fine as
long as it looks nice that will be the
main thing
the only problem now is that i've
actually started this project without
getting all of the resources that i need
because of the civil war i've basically
run out of most of the materials i used
a lot of my own materials to make the
g-team base and that has ended up
meaning that i'm now
very low on resources all around i'm
down to my last diamond and i really
don't have a lot of concrete left and
i've definitely run low on terracotta so
in order to be able to finish this train
this train station at all i'm gonna have
to go on a bit of a grind so
unfortunately that's all that i've got
time for today but the main thing that i
want everyone to take home from this is
that grian me
mr awful redstone has actually managed
to make a functioning farm minus two
villages so let's take a look underneath
has it been working
yes yes it has it has been absolutely
working and it's produced a fair amount
of potatoes i imagine that this will
fill up incredibly quickly incredibly
quickly in fact i'm gonna have to even
consider doing a proper storage system
for this or get it autos uh cooking
those things well that's it for me and
i'm actually away for about a week so
unfortunately this may be the last
episode for a little while because i'm
obviously gonna be disconnecting and i'm
gonna be trying to relax a little bit
and i should come back fresh as a daisy
and ready to go full steam on the next
project did i just throw that in the
portal
i did
i
no tried and come back
i think i just i've lost my trident
that was really bad
so anyway thank you very much for
watching and hopefully there'll be a new
episode within the next week i've even
created a little to-do list for me and
i'm going to get these did you die boxes
done and then we can go full steam ahead
after i've invited iscam now where did i
put
that piece of paper it says iskall on it
no not that one
no
where's the iscal architect lol
where is
no just a piece of paper
you know what i can't find the letter
i i honestly can't find the letter um
oh dear
maybe i'll um
maybe i dropped it in the portal
somewhere
i have a feeling that i maybe lost it in
the portal because i started like
dumping my stuff here like this and oh
actually i want that back
but i think i actually put the paper
through here
and it's been lost in the void
i don't know i honestly don't know but
we're gonna have to figure it out anyway
thanks again for watching and good bye